Erica Goodwin Frontend Developer

Email: ericagoodwin90@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://ejgoodwin.github.io/portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/ejgoodwin

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/erica-goodwin-4b6b64112/

Skills / Experience

• HTML, CSS3, SASS, BEM

- JavaScript, jQuery, React.js
- · WordPress (custom theme development), PHP
- Java (university assignments)
- Git
- UI design
- · Adobe Creative Cloud
- Responsive design and development

Personal Profile

I am enthusiastic about UI and frontend development. In my current role I have brought in a pattern library, which I want use as part of a wider design system. The pattern library ensure new features and designs are consistent with our branding, and encourage higher standards. My creative background has been useful in keeping a sharp eye for detail while developing components and ensuring they render on the page correctly. I am now studying a Master's degree in computer science to broaden my technical knowledge and to develop a logical way of thinking that is required with the problem solving aspect of development work.

I have been involved in the entire lifecycle of websites: design, converting designs to functional sites (HTML, CSS, jQuery, PHP), and deployment. Throughout the process I liaise with clients, account managers and designers to assess and implement the best solutions. All sites are fully responsive and cross browser tested.

Work Experience

Designer / UI Frontend Developer

Straker Translations (Auckland, NZ), Aug 2019 - present

- Redesigning and developing the UI of web applications
- I develop the front end, and then hand over to backend developers to integrate the new UI into our applications
- I Introduced a style guide and pattern library to ensure consistency for design and development

Web Design and Frontend Development

ARA (Sydney, Australia), Nov 2018 - May 2019 (6 month contract)

- Built and maintained websites for ARA companies and internal projects
- · Worked with React.js and WordPress built custom themes from scratch
- Created full website designs to be approved by the client
- · Built fully functional, responsive websites from designs

Web Designer

Adtrak (Nottingham, UK), Jan 2017 - June 2018

- Designed and coded websites using WordPress CMS built custom themes from scratch
- Worked closely with clients, utilised InVision to enable the client to view and comment on the design
- · Liaised with other departments and clients to deliver sites that are functional and perform well
- · Worked through the entire process from design to code to deployment
- Experienced in setting sites live, transferring domains, handling databases

Academic Support Worker

The Learning Support Centre (Leicester, UK), March 2015 - March 2016

- Supported students with learning difficulties and/or disabilities in academic situations, including lectures and exams
- · Provided transcription work for visually impaired
- Built trusting, professional relationships and responded to needs of clients/service users

Education

MSc Computer Science (online)

York University 2019 - present

I am studying online for a MSc in CS. I have worked on the following modules: algorithms & data structures, software engineering, data analytics, and computer architecture & operating systems.

BA(Hons) Fine Art

De Montfort University 2013 - 2016

Art and Design (Foundation Studies) BTEC Diploma

De Montfort University 2012 - 2013

Queen Elizabeth II College

A Levels: Art - B; Photography - D

AS Levels: Art - A; English Literature - D; Photography - C; Graphics - D

Sir Jonathon North Community College GCSE Grades - 5As, 3Bs, 1C, 1D

Interests

I am exploring some react.js projects, deepening my knowledge on creating a UI with states. If I'm not studying, I like to venture out to the countryside and explore the wilderness. I also enjoy finding some fun bars, meeting new people, and the odd wine & paint night.